Right.
So we're on
waiting room enabled.
Alright,
here we go.
Here. Those tools.
Um,
hold and,
okay, cool.
Little quizzes? Nope.
Okay, so I'm gonna change this to, um,
the chat participants.
Josh, can you hear me?
Yeah. Sorry, I was just, uh, I ran
to the restroom real quick.
Um, let me change my name
Real quick.
Did you log in to admin as well?
Uh, I think I was already like, logged in.
It gave me a message just saying.
Okay. Yeah, I, I, that's why I messaged you.
'cause I was like, I, I had to log in.
I've been logged out of it in light
of the little snafu you had just in case.
Yeah. But, but I had to come in
and like do the polls and stuff, so.
Yeah. Yeah, it just gives me the option to reclaim
or re remain co-host, so. Okay.
Okay. So this is, uh, I will, uh,
let me just rename,
um, the host I, 'cause I believe I'm the host Josh.
Cool.
You send me the, uh, link to the gamma, by the way.
Um, I, I'll do it right now. Thanks. Because
You, you, you told me to do the slides, right?
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Yeah,
I just, I just wanna give
it a quick review before we start.
Oh, gotcha. Yeah. Here we go.
Yes,
Lord.
Remind yourself on the, the operating system.
It's, uh, just somewhat confusing.
'cause I'm, I literally just did, uh,
the last session in teams twice.
Mm-hmm. Oh, did you Yesterday? Yeah.
It's like, what am doing again? Nice.
All right. Let me get this note. Take outta here.
And then you're sharing a screen, right?
Yeah. I'll end up just doing it 'cause I'll share
and then, 'cause I'm doing the slides.
So, because it was funny too,
'cause like the last, uh, I think it was the last session,
um, we were like, uh, Midori and I were sitting here
and we're like, oh my God, there's like one person here.
And, and, um, but then when we launched it, like,
you know, everybody came in.
So the calls have, the calls have been around.
Um, I like 10 to 15 people. So a little more intimate.
I think. Um, people were, I joked with VPO that, like,
on the first call, you know, it was probably like 15 people.
And with so many beta people, they were like, oh, wow.
I was expecting this to be like the beta with like 50.
And in my head, I mean, what I said was like,
well, we wanna keep this intimate.
Make sure you get your attention. In
my head I was like, yeah, me too.
You know, it's like, yeah, it's exactly what we wanted. But,
Um, I did the, the, the stuff yesterday, by the way,
I know we, we don't have like a meeting today,
but if you want to, um, jump on with me for,
'cause like, I didn't notice any, um, errors per se.
Uh, there was one piece of, like, the last thing that I did.
Um, I, I forgot what exercise it is.
Um, but basically the last thing inside Claude,
when I ran it, it was like in Claude, it told me, Hey,
add this to the end of your master prompt, end
to stage three, which is kind of
what I've been doing the whole time.
But then I noticed in your directions on the doc,
it only says to put it in stage three.
And so I was like, I I was gonna tell you like, hey, just,
it's not a big deal, but I'm sure it's both.
It's just not mentioned on the doc too, probably.
Okay. Um, yeah, we, we can connect quickly afterwards.
Okay. 'cause I, I'll have something to send you as well.
Okay, cool. But, um,
I, I deleted the three hag way thing.
'cause I, I guess Dale must have added that. We did not.
I've never used it.
Oh, yeah, Dale definitely added it.
I, I guess like I Oh, okay. You deleted it.
Well, it's in the poll.
Oh, really? Okay. I I'll undo it. Yeah.
Don't report to Zoom.
Yeah, that's, that's just something Dale added.
So we talk about being an operating system here.
What's that? Okay. We talked about being an operating
system here when we had talked about
before wanting to call it like a framework
and not an operating system, but whatever. Yeah. I mean,
Yeah, that, well, this was, this was kind of like
before we, uh, we kind of got into that.
So what I'll do, if you want, I,
I'll like launch it like one
after that way we're, you know, like, sure.
Everybody's, everybody's like, in the waiting room,
and then we'll just kind of go, go from there.
So, we'll wait, I know it's one o'clock right now,
but we'll just, I'll launch,
I'll admit all at like one oh one
Missed call
In the last session. We
already went through the five stages, right?
That was in session two. Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Yeah. All everybody here is, uh, one to three.
So mostly one and three,
and kind of some people at stage two.
So, okay, cool. So I'll just let, uh,
I'll just let everybody in and we can get started.
Mm-hmm.
Happy Friday. Yeah, happy Friday.
I'll say to most of you, uh, there,
there's definitely people all over
the world, but happy Friday.
Good afternoon, or morning
or evening, wherever you're kind of logging in from.
I'm just gonna give about 30 seconds just, uh,
to give people kind of like the, the chance
to, to log on here.
And then I'll kind of open it up for everybody to, to join
after we, we get started.
But how's everybody
wrapping up their, their first week?
Anybody want to put in the chat? Starting to feeling good?
Some of you beta cohorts, are you, um, just outta curiosity,
are you starting from scratch, um, like we discussed,
or are, are some of you taking it like, Hey,
I just wanna redo a, a couple pieces
of the business as we go through.
So just check here. Okay.
Round two fresh. Okay. Cool. Nice. Good to see that.
Start room scratch. Okay. Good. All right, sweet.
So this is all a hundred percent relevant for everybody.
Okay, great.
I will open stuff up and then we can just get started
and everybody can, can kind of come in.
Let's see. Share my screen.
Alright. Alright.
Can you all see my slides here? Okay.
Perfect. Well, I wanna welcome everyone to
live session three.
It's great to see you all here as we kind
of like wrap up the, the first week.
Now for today's session,
the focus is on gaining a clear understanding of the
Empower framework, which is what drives how we think,
make decisions, and kind of take action within Empower Labs.
We'll also explore the assessments
and implementation tools that kind of build on this system.
Giving you a, a structured way to measure progress and,
and put everything into practice as we continue here.
Alright, let's go over where we are in the program.
So we're at session three.
You've done the, the foundational work in sessions one
and two, getting your master prompt set up,
and then understanding AI first,
thinking now we're shifting into something that's gonna kind
of tie everything together.
That's the Empower Operating System.
This is where we'll start to build the actual framework
that will help you systematically improve every part
of your business using ai.
Okay, before we jump in,
I wanna do a quick milestone check-in.
It's good to see that everyone's kind
of starting from scratch, uh, getting this thing built,
but I just wanna see, um, this is exactly
where you should be at this particular point in time.
So you should understand the customer likes the Lifecycle
three business or three layers of, of business processes
and RACI through those reading exercises,
you've added shared language to your master prompt,
and you've added company resources to your master prompt.
Um, and in the, the recap, this should be a total
of about five project files
inside your master prompt project right now.
So what I'm gonna do is I wanna launch a poll,
and I just want to see exactly where people are at,
whether you're done partially done or you haven't started.
So launching that poll right now.
Okay. So 50 oh oh, more votes coming in.
Okay, so everybody's in, I'll end the poll,
share the results for you all to see here on the screen.
But pretty much, you know, uh, half of you are done, half
of you are partially done, and,
and one person hasn't started.
So, really quickly, for the one person who hasn't started,
I'm not sure if you want to unmute yourself
and, and speak up briefly.
Um, but is is the reason for you not starting?
Was it just because you, you started late
and you're just playing catch up just out of curiosity?
Or you, you haven't made the time just to, to do it?
All right. All right.
So we don't, we don't need to speak up,
but, you know, since it's only one person,
I just wanna reiterate, you know, try
to do these the best we can, um, on time, uh, especially
after this session.
Uh, for clarity, um, you will start to run
behind fairly quickly
as we really start getting into assessments
after this session.
So we will, I'll go cover what, uh,
we're actually doing today.
This session will have three parts.
Part one, we're gonna explore different operating
systems, not just Empower.
We're talking about EOS, great game of business,
scaling up all the big ones.
And we're, we're doing that
because some of you already use these
and we wanna show you how Empower fits into
or enhances what you're already doing.
Part two, we're introducing Empower itself.
Hayden is here, who's the, the creator of it.
He's gonna kind of walk you through, you know,
what makes it different, why it's designed the way
that it is, and how it's specifically built
for the AI enabled business.
And then part three, this is kind of the practical stuff
where revealing the assessment tool and,
and showing you how to create your first
SOPs using AI following this session.
So, um, you're gonna leave here
with the actual work product.
And with that, I will hand it on over to Hayden to,
to kick off part one.
Thanks, Josh. Uh, nice to meet everybody.
Uh, as Josh said, I, I started, uh, the company with, uh,
Tiago Forte about, uh, six months ago.
We ran the first beta cohort, so some
of the faces here are familiar.
Um, and yeah, uh, a lot
of it was based on previous operating systems.
So I wanted to chat a little bit about, uh, the, sort
of the inspiration behind it.
Um, so I've been a bit of a operating system nerd, uh,
probably over the last decade or so.
I've probably implemented, I've implemented every single one
of these in various companies.
Um, and I've seen really strong implementations through, uh,
sort of my business purchasing activities,
uh, of most of them as well.
Um, probably the most famous, uh,
or that people will be, uh, aware of is Traction or EOS.
Traction is a fantastic introduction to operating systems.
And its simplicity is really its strength.
The weakness that I, I think a lot of people find
with track traction as they get into it is, uh, a lack
of specifics.
So a lack of sort of specifics around
how do you create process, uh, specifics around leadership.
Um, and so often I, I find
that traction ends up being like the entry
point into operating systems.
And then, uh,
people end up moving up into something like scaling up.
Uh, scaling Up is, if no one's read the book,
there's a book called Scaling Up by Vern Harnish.
It's a very robust system.
Um, what I like about it is, is if like traction is Apple
with a closed ecosystem, uh, scaling up is open source.
And if you read that book,
you'll probably read about 25 other books while you're
reading it because they reference,
if you wanna do this, go check out this.
If you wanna do this, go check out that.
Um, it is a full implementation.
Scaling up is probably three plus years.
Uh, so it's, it's quite complex.
Um, scalable is a, if people aren't familiar, scalable is
by Ryan Deiss, uh, he's Ryan Digital marketer
and some other businesses, uh, it's an interesting,
I would say like an in-between, uh,
between Scaling Up and Traction.
Uh, it teaches process quite, it's a very good introduction
to process, but it's very manual.
Um, so his whole thing is to build a growth engine
and a fulfillment engine.
Um, but I would also say it, it kind
of lacks a holistic strategic approach, much like traction.
Um, so, uh, the great game
of business is a very, is an interesting one.
I actually just came, went to a, uh,
workshop, uh, a few months ago.
And it, and it is, uh,
it's an operating system based on open book management
and based on employee ownership
and financial literacy, uh, they,
they take this concept of, um, sort
of bottoms up innovation
and bottoms up forecasting to, uh, the best I've ever seen.
And I think they have 40 straight years of, uh, growth
and have grown something like 10 x Berkshire Hathaway, uh,
incredible, incredible business, uh, that they were touring.
Um, but it is fairly
rooted in sort of manufacturing, uh,
and not that popular unfortunately.
Um, the, I I mentioned all
of these because some of you may be using these
operating systems already.
Some of you may be aware of 'em, maybe you've also kind
of tried implementing them,
and, uh, they've been, it's been hard
to get traction, uh, in it.
Um, I, I have nothing against any of the operating systems.
I think it's great to use a, an operating system.
Um, I ended up creating my own
for the businesses that we buy.
Uh, and, but I've tried them all out.
Uh, what we ended up creating,
you wanna go to the next slide.
Um, what we ended up creating kind of
supplements, uh, with the pieces
that I find are often missing.
Um, so it supplements with process, uh, it supplements
with some leadership, obviously with ai.
Um, for those who, who are like lifeline learners.
Uh, this slide is kind of some of the books that I recommend
to the leadership teams, um, that we,
after we buy a company, we form leadership teams.
And these are all the books that I mentioned.
Um, usually, uh, in this session, uh, I'll sort
of mention some of them and other people, if you like, uh,
want to, uh, put in the chat other books that you've read.
I, I find this is a great way to just kind of share for,
for all of the, uh, learners out there.
Um, on the leadership side, uh, radical Candor,
which is more of a management book, uh, is a book
that we make necessary reading for all managers, uh,
and especially all first time managers.
Um, seven Habits of Highly Effective People.
Probably most of you have read that. Uh, I probably reread
that once every three or four years.
Uh, crucial Conversations also a a great, great book, uh,
especially if you're going through, uh, a difficult period
or having to have a difficult
conversation, uh, with someone.
And on the financial literacy side, uh,
financial intelligence is also, uh, required reading
for all our leadership teams.
Um, it's a great way to introduce financial literacy,
uh, to people in a non overwhelming way.
Uh, and I really believe that, uh,
financial literacy is like a, a foundation, uh,
that everyone needs to build on.
Um, and then on the innovation side, uh, there are
books that teach interesting mental
models around innovation.
Um, so, and all, all of these are actually very useful
to work with AI on.
Um, so for example, uh, all of the Strategizer tools, uh,
have some interesting approaches
to like defining innovation, uh,
which I find are significantly more useful today, now
that you can work with ai, and AI is already aware of them.
You can literally just introduce them, uh,
and have them just create an artifact, uh, all of the images
and models you want.
Um, the Lean Startup is a great framework for those who, uh,
it is mainly based on sort of the Silicon Valley idea
of minimum viable products and, and test product testing.
Um, and Exponential Organizations is actually a book
that was introduced to me from someone in the beta cohort,
uh, and is an excellent, excellent book on, uh,
introducing innovation, um, with some
of the exponential technologies coming out.
Um, ISO 9,001 is a quality management standard.
Uh, it's typically used, uh,
in larger manufacturing companies, uh,
but it is actually one of those,
I would say, frameworks
that AI can help you implement within your business.
And much of what we're doing here,
it actually builds upon some of the basics of ISO 9,001, um,
and it, and top grading, uh, which is a
method for hiring, uh, and,
and onboarding, um, of employees are two fantastic,
uh, frameworks that I've always attempted
to implement in my businesses, have
historically taken over a year to implement
and probably cost me a lot of money.
Um, and today are now basically introduced as part
of the onboarding, um, from day one
because of AI within, you know, the first two months.
Um, so if you haven't, uh,
got a basic foundation of what those two things are,
I'd highly recommend like watching a YouTube video about
it or reading a book about it.
We're teaching a lot of this, um, as we go, um,
but we're probably not getting the full foundation, uh, as
to the why on a lot of it.
So I would recommend, uh, you check those out.
Has anyone read any of these books
or have any, uh, other opinions to share?
You could put it in the chat if you guys want.
Okay. Someone's got a, a med tech industry standard.
ISO. Yeah.
Yeah. Nancy has definitely read the seven habits.
Uh, two are missing.
What is two are missing? Yeah,
What is that? Is it a, is
it a book, Christian?
Sorry. No, um, I was just not reading two of them.
Oh, interesting. Crucial
Conversations is already in my, uh, bucket.
And, um, and the exponential
organizations 2.0, the rest I know.
Awesome. So, um,
hi Hayden, Dr. Good to see you again.
Uh, I just wanted to mention that, you know, the,
the reading list is fabulous.
Uh, and I found myself, uh, dumping as much of
that into the notebook LM as I could
because it was so much to absorb
and, uh, creating these, uh, infographics
that helped me remember, know what to pay attention to.
And so, uh, yeah, suck it up, right?
Yeah, great tip. Yeah.
Yeah, for those who haven't used,
Yeah, it's really cool, Don and,
and everybody else, I don't know, as you,
as you build this system out, it's really cool to kind
of like the, the idea of, of all of this knowledge,
whether it's from these books or great
entrepreneurs in the past, right?
Like Hayden, I think you've
referenced like the what would Jesus do.
You could be like, Hey, what would, you know,
Rockefeller do, or whoever you sort of follow,
their knowledge is out there,
and it's interesting to, uh, continue to build knowledge
and be able to cite from that in certain situations.
So that's pretty cool.
And AI is this ultimate, um, democratizer of a lot
of these frameworks that would've been really expensive
to implement in a smaller business.
Uh, and so, like in this, within this cohort,
we are really looking at a few of these items,
but I would encourage people to just, if you've read a book,
um, and are curious, uh, spend an hour
or two just chatting with Claude, um,
specifically about some of the strategic plans
or the, the canvases that they do,
and have Claude just, you know, code something for you.
Um, I remember one day I was chatting with Dale
and I was reminded of Strategizer.
I had, I hadn't thought about it in years.
Um, and I just ended up creating like,
the business model canvas for one of my businesses
and going back and forth, and it was excellent.
Um, so much more useful today than it would've been,
than it was for me like four
or five years ago when I last looked at it.
Just because, you know, the amount of work it took
to really think about it before was hours
and hours, if not days of work.
And now it's, you know, minutes, um,
to get something valuable out of it.
Yeah, I, uh, I asked, uh, Claude what, uh,
Jay Paul Getty would do with other stuff, and it told me
It is pretty fascinating.
All right, I'm gonna launch a poll here just
to get a gauge on everybody, so it'll be one poll,
but just, just so we have an idea,
no different than yesterday, we found out
what stage you're at, right?
So now we wanna just launch this poll asking which
of the operating systems any of you have used in the past,
and then sort of to Hayden's point, you know, at, at
what level did you sort of implement that once you decided
to, you know, take, take traction or, or anything else.
So I'm gonna launch that poll now.
So it's, it's two questions.
Once you do the first one, just keep scrolling down
for the implementation part.
All right.
Just waiting on a few more people to vote.
All right. I think one did input, I'm gonna end it
and share the results here.
So, as you can see, uh, most people scaling up,
I actually think Hayden, this is the first time
traction wasn't the, uh,
wasn't the number one in all the cohorts,
so that's interesting to see.
Um, but 40% scaling up, 30% traction,
and then, you know, everything
but the great game of business got got some votes.
Really cool. It's cool to see that.
Um, anybody who put other,
before I move on, I,
I would be a little curious if you put in the chat
what operating system you've, uh, you've implemented.
That would be kind of cool to know.
And then on the, the, the tag to that,
let's see what you put here.
BM Canvas. Okay, I'm not familiar with that.
Benny Hayden, have you heard of that?
That's the strategizer one,
Yeah. Okay.
Um, value proposition design,
strategizer business model.
Okay. Mm-hmm. Okay. Alright. Thank you Rachel.
And then, yeah, it looks like a lot of you, um, 40%
of you voted, uh, two out of five in terms
of implemented it.
Um, if anybody wants to share, uh, you can unmute yourself,
but, um, and,
and it would be good to know, you know,
maybe give 30 seconds on, on what you found
to be the challenge when sort of taking
that to your organization.
Business model Canvas, I always
have problems to adapt
and readapt, uh, the value proposition.
That's the most, uh, crucial part.
And, uh, this, this, I'm, I'm never to the point
I, I don't know if this is normal, maybe,
but, uh, I let, let hear others.
When you say adat, the value proposition, is it
because your, your ICP is changing over time,
or you're introducing new products and services or,
Yeah, I, it is, um, if a,
a business model is not working properly mm-hmm.
Then you try to address, uh, um, on one side the product
or the service, again, to the same target groups.
Mm-hmm. Or the other side is, um,
you change the target groups.
Mm-hmm. So mainly,
and that's, uh, what we tried
after 3, 4, 4, 5 years.
So my stomach feeling
after three years was, Hey, we need
to stop it, but my board,
Uh, oh, That's not me. Right?
No, no, it's not me. I think it's Benny.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Benny,
You were, you were a little cut off.
If you can hear us. Uh, we, we are gonna, um,
what we'll do is, we'll, we'll keep moving,
Hayden, just get into part two.
Yep. Introducing Empower for everybody.
Sure.
So what is Empower?
Um, empower is, I,
it's an operating system slash framework.
Um, so I would actually say like, operating systems
introduce, uh, a lot of disciplines.
And so it's more of a framework
to a company operating systems.
Um, but it's designed to, uh, actually fill in, in a lot
of areas where operating systems lack, uh,
and one of those is process creation.
Um, so hopefully in the last couple sessions,
everyone understands the value of, of sort
of a process driven BI business,
and especially how that values amplified today, now
that AI can run those processes.
Um, so what we are using with Empower is a framework
to evaluate your current processes, like the,
the customer lifecycle, plus a two to three other, uh,
processes that I've found in my experience,
small businesses, um, really could use help with, um,
and just understand how to, uh, enhance those processes, uh,
see what experience and,
and see what, uh, great looks like in those processes.
Uh, and then actually start implementing, uh, AI
and building workflows, orent solutions into them.
Uh, it started out actually as a bit of a audit checklist,
uh, for when I was evaluating companies to purchase.
Uh, and then it evolved over the years into our own
operating system that we used for change management.
Um, so we sort of score, we buy the business.
We had this sort of intrinsic value
that was across each of those factors.
Uh, and the goal was to kind of do changes to the company
to improve the intrinsic value, um, over time.
And so there was this kind of, this constant assessment, um,
that was going back and forth that we automated quite a bit.
Um, one of the things that, that we found, uh,
as we bought new companies, um, was that
as we put leadership teams in place, like the,
the most important thing that we could do early on
was I actually get them tours of other businesses,
whether they were our businesses
or, uh, you know, businesses in some
of the operating systems that, uh, did tours, uh, just so
that they could understand what great looked like, uh,
and also so they could understand what, you know, the nuance
of, of what great looks like, right?
So you would do a tour of a company that had a great culture
and a great company culture.
Um, you could do a tour of a company
that had a great sales process, right?
You could do a tour of a company that, um,
had fantastic training, um,
and that kind of transformed into how can we also use AI to
teach what great looks like in each of these different,
um, key functions.
Um, so that, that's kinda the history of it.
Uh, and now it's being used more, uh, as a,
as an assessment and improvement tool.
So, going along with the acronym, uh, the rest
of this cohort, uh, well, except for the last two sessions,
um, are actually just covering one
of the, uh, value drivers.
So one of the letters of Empower.
Uh, so today we're actually gonna get into, in the homework,
we're gonna get into the beginnings
of the expansion capability capability, um, which is kind
of going over the sale to delivery and delivery to success.
Um, the next session will be session four, which is delivery
to success, which also goes over customer success
as a function, which many businesses, uh, if you're not sort
of in the SaaS world, many of the businesses kind of ignore.
Um, but I, I feel is, uh, extremely important.
Session five is marketing and brand equity.
And so we're gonna go over
what great looks like in marketing.
Uh, everyone's gonna go through an assessment, uh,
with Claude based on their company.
They're gonna learn, put together like a,
a cool little fractional CMO prompt.
Uh, a lot of people have gotten a lot of use out of that.
And we're also gonna be building out our
marketing processes.
Uh, session six, uh, is in profitability metrics.
So this is your finance performance management.
Uh, same thing. What does good look like?
Uh, assess yourself, build out the process.
Fractional CFO, prompt, uh,
session seven is offering a sales effectiveness.
So that's the lead to sale process.
I, and Josh has a lot of great value he'll be adding there.
Uh, and then workforce
and leadership is the, we call it people
and culture in our companies.
Um, some people call it hr.
I think, uh, I, I like hr,
but if you call it the hire to retire process, um,
and that, that's super interesting.
Um, lots of interesting, uh, advancements there.
I'm actually, uh, we've actually added, uh,
some clarity boards on how to do it in ai,
and this is, that'll be something new for the beta people
that, that will be bringing in.
Um, session nine, uh, is execution system.
So here we're gonna go into like quality management,
and how do you, you know, it's not one thing
to make these processes,
but how do you actually start implementing them?
Um, and do you do it bottoms up? Do you do it top down?
Um, we're gonna go over all of that.
Session 10 is the robust market position,
which is actually the product service design process, uh,
which is like,
and go to market process, which is just
so much easier today with ai.
Um, I, I felt I had to improve. I include that.
So what separates Empower as a framework, uh, from a lot
of the other oss, uh, like I said, it's not intended really
to replace an os, it's, it's intended to supplement, uh,
where I feel a lot of those oss are a little weaker.
Um, and so one of those areas is, is being process focused.
Um, so, you know, traction
and scaling up both tell you that data
and process is important,
but they don't really tell you
how do you actually go about creating it.
Uh, and for those who use ISO or those who've done like BPM
and business, business process management,
it seems overwhelmingly complex, um, when it doesn't have
to be, uh, value centered.
Um, so one thing that as someone who, who buys
and sells and consolidates businesses for a living, um,
I find it frustrating that everything isn't value centered,
like what actually creates enterprise value in a company.
Um, I think most of you're probably business owners, I
most of you probably if at some point want to, um,
get some level of liquidity, whether that means
actually selling the business, whether that means, you know,
selling it to employees, whether that means something else.
You know, I, and,
and that honestly, uh, is what
the exit and liquidity side of business is probably
what makes entrepreneurship, uh, financially worth it.
There's a lot of reasons it's worth it for, you know,
your lifestyle, and if you're like
me and you're just unemployable.
Um, but for financial reasons, I,
it, it, it's the tax side of selling, um, that,
that I think is really valuable.
Um, and then implementing implementation oriented.
So I've intended this to be highly practical, um,
and that also allows it to work very well with ai.
Um, we can go to the next slide. Yep.
So last session, we went over the five stages, uh,
and we went over, you know, it's a, it's nice
to call it like the five stages of business.
It's, it's really the five stages of a process, right?
So you can have, uh,
your marketing be process driven while your sales is heroic.
Effort is, is, is stage one, right?
Um, so, so when I say
that these have different exit multiples, I mean, we have
to take into account, um, is it sort of the majority
of the business at that stage, right?
Um, when we buy businesses, we personally, we, we focus on
actually buying a lot of these stage one businesses
because they're cheap, right?
Uh, typically you're looking at under, let's say one
and a half million dollars in ebitda, right?
So say somewhere under 10 million in revenue, uh,
and often no leadership team really in place.
If you look at an org chart, um, which doesn't exist,
it would basically be a,
a circle orbiting a founder or a pair of founders.
Um, and you know, that, that became my specialty
or our company's specialty, was
how do we take heroic effort businesses
and turn them into team led
and process driven businesses as quickly as possible?
Um, the reason they,
they treat trade cheaply is you actually do have
to invest quite a, a bit into growing them.
And their, their margins are ebitda margins are,
are frankly like unsustainable, uh, for a non another owner,
um, to buy and operate.
Um, typically, obviously the EBITDA employee here,
obviously, industries vary drastically.
Um, I think if you look at this, it's probably better
to just look at like the range
or the, the multiple range between each of them.
So I, there's actually not a massive difference between,
uh, a stage one
and a stage two business, an EBITDA per employee.
Um, in some cases with very small businesses,
you actually have higher EBITDA per employee on a,
on a stage one business because you just have a really legit
founder who's probably working three or four jobs.
Um, but it's, it's completely unsustainable.
Um, if you see yourself primarily as a stage one business
and you want it to sell, uh, your business,
or you wanted to, you know, bring on investment, uh,
you would probably be doing that at about a two
to three x EBITDA multiple.
So if, if your business has a million dollars today,
you maybe would sell it for three.
Um, in my opinion, I,
it's not a ton of effort to get to sort of that stage two
or low stage three side
and immediately get significantly higher liquidity.
Um, so highly suggest working
with a framework to, to help you do that.
Uh, stage two is team led.
So we probably went over this a bit in the last session,
but I'll, it's, it's worth repeating.
Um, so team led, I,
you can have levels of process in place, uh, and,
and in many cases, uh, team led has process documents
that just process isn't followed, uh,
and processes often outta date.
Um, team led ends up becoming the,
the limitation on scale ends up actually being,
uh, death by meeting.
So if a lot of, if a lot of
decisions in the business, uh, are, let's say for example,
if you review scorecards in a meeting, right?
And you make decisions based on KPIs, based on that, if, uh,
certain processes require a meeting to move forward, uh,
that's where, that's really where stage two kind of, um,
ends up bottlenecking stage three, it's process driven.
So that, that means that you actually have, um, you know,
usually you have scorecards that are dynamic
and anyone can load up at any point.
You have workflows in place where, you know,
you have these templated instances of workflows
where things automatically get loaded into people's, uh,
ERP or CRMs.
Um, and that's when EBITDA per employee,
um, starts to go up.
Uh, and it's also the necessary step
to becoming AI augmented.
Um, so I would say that there's like workflow augmented,
and there's AI augmented,
and if you are like watching YouTube videos, there's not
that much difference between the two of them.
Um, you know, the, the main difference today is that,
you know, in most of those workflows, you can,
you can use a prompt to assess, um,
but that's not actually that different.
Um, the AI operated side of this, uh, again,
this is still somewhat fantastical,
and there are certainly some functions of a business
that are ai, AI operated.
Um, the very few businesses that are actually running like
that, uh, the, the difference there is that
you have agents instead of workflows.
And, and what an agent is,
is it's almost like a AI employee, right?
They have an actual role, they have, uh, an outcome
that they're building towards.
They have tools and subagents
and have the ability to spin up subagents
and orchestrate things to actually get to that outcome.
So they actually do exception handling, right?
Whereas in the AI augmented business, you know,
humans are there to do all exception handling.
Um, I, I would say this is gonna become more
and more common in 2026.
Everyone says this is the year of the agent
and the year of orchestration.
Um, and so, you know, by 2027, I think a a lot
of people will have a lot of their functions here.
Um, one of the things that we're gonna go over in a future
session is designing your AI first competitor with cloud
and understanding what that looks like.
Um, because there will be certain functions
that are AI operated, um, that will, you know, drive
marginal cost down to next 10.
So if you wanna do about two minutes, uh,
maybe deep Hayden just to focus on the,
the key value drivers as you, you already kind
of covered here through empower.
Yep. Uh, yeah.
So yeah, we went through these, I'll, I'll repeat them.
Um, so sale to delivery, uh,
and delivery to success is the fulfillment side, uh,
of, of your business.
Um, so if you have an event planning business, sale
to delivery may end up being your onboarding, uh,
and planning and delivery
to success may end up being the actual event management.
Um, they, I separated them.
Most people just call it fulfillment, right?
I've separated them for a couple different reasons.
Um, one, one is to simplify it and,
and to just to add, uh, a level of nuance.
Uh, again, if you have like an e-commerce business
that is an impulse buy, you know,
low ticket impulse buy your sale to delivery is,
is gonna be very, very simple, right?
Um, but if you have a considered purchase,
which we'll go over something that requires, you know,
consideration, potentially multiple people, uh,
making decision, a long timeline, sale to delivery,
and se segmenting out,
sale delivery becomes extremely valuable.
Uh, delivery to success, same thing.
Um, the, the concept of customer success, uh,
which we'll go over in a, in a future session, um,
is not just, you know, you delivered your product
or service, right?
It's, it's actually having success
with that product and service.
Um, but we'll get into that in two sessions.
So marketing actually covers two, uh, processes.
So one is market to lead.
Um, and so it's important to understand, a lot of people say
customer acquisition, right?
Uh, and they combine marketing with sales.
Uh, I, that's a mistake in my opinion.
Um, and in fact, you shouldn't even have the same people
ideally covering those two.
Um, so market to lead is basically how do you expose
your business to the market
and then turn it into a lead, you know,
get a per get permission to contact them, uh, lead to sales,
how do you take those leads and turn them into sales?
And so, aspects of lead to sale,
or blueprints of lead
to sale would include things like lead scoring, right?
Or having lead stages.
How do people exit one stage and enter another stage?
Um, and so again, a lot of this you'll see is,
is segmentation.
So taking something that, uh, was one word
and maybe accomp accompanied a lot
of different things like customer acquisition
and splitting them into smaller
and smaller segments that you can visualize
and then create process around success to market is, uh,
so I mentioned customer success.
Uh, in the last slide, success to market is
how do you take the customer successes
and then expose 'em to the market?
So how do you have a process that collects testimonials,
collects reviews, uh, posts them, et cetera, uh,
because that creates a flywheel of success for the company.
And it also creates a, a content flywheel, uh,
for the company, which, uh, again, with ai, uh,
it becomes extremely easy, uh, to create
and to distribute
profitability metrics.
So basically, financial performance, ma management, uh,
we also call it books to insights.
Uh, so how well do you track
and understand, optimize your financial performance?
I, for this is often a, for people
who don't come from a finance background, this is often, um,
a bit of a, a struggle, uh,
and it's, there, there are certain tools
that everyone should be using.
Um, and for those who, uh, aren't
fantastic with spreadsheets, uh, the good news is that,
that Claude is, is fantastic with spreadsheets
and also is fantastic with creating, you know, dynamic
coded reports for you, uh, which we'll get into.
Uh, do you wanna cover this one, Josh?
Yeah. Yeah. It's, uh, offering and sales effectiveness.
It's as says here, you know, it covers the, the lead
to sale core process.
Um, so how effectively you kind of convert
prospects into customers,
and it also covers your unique value proposition,
something Benny talked about,
and kind of how to position it in, in the future, you know,
where Hayden talks about execution being democratized.
So, um, I'll lead this session.
It's kind of what I focused on for, for the past five years.
A lot, um, internally here with Hayden,
but also at, um, dozens of other companies.
So, so it'll, it'll just be covering those things.
AI is super interesting on the, on the sales side, um,
especially if, uh, you do sales online, uh,
and sort of are, are recording it.
Uh, there's a lot of cool stuff there.
Uh, we'll probably share it more in the office hours.
Um, workforce
and leadership, I, so this is the Hire
to Retire enabling process.
This is something because I primarily bought service
businesses over the last, uh, five or six years.
This is something we really focused on
because one of the largest constraints was demand,
uh, sorry, supply.
So how, how do you actually ideally, like,
create and train a workforce?
Um, and this is another area that AI has just made something
that was once difficult, um, super, super accessible.
Uh, I, if people watch some of the early, like,
master prompt videos on, you know, the hiring
as a hiring framework, um, those are examples
of things that you can do with it.
Um, so execution systems, uh, you will be
learning about the fascinating world
of quality management systems.
Uh, so how do you actually embed execution
into tools and systems?
This is, uh, some people don't love
to crack the whip.
Uh, I am one of those people.
Uh, and so how can you actually create systems
to do a lot of that for you?
Um, how do you track KPIs and exceptions?
How do you do internal audits?
How do you have, you know, audit trails, um, for your tasks?
How do you use tools like, you know,
Zapier to do a lot of this?
Um, we're gonna cover quite a bit, uh, of that.
And again, this is a space that is extremely, uh,
disrupted by ai, uh, makes it a lot more accessible.
Uh, and if you're like me and you don't love doing this, uh,
and you always felt you needed like a right hand man
who was an a*****e to crack the whip, uh, you know,
good news, AI can be that person
and we'll do it very pleasantly.
And then the r here is a robust market position.
Um, so this is, this is somewhat, uh,
we, we cheated a little bit.
Uh, the r in terms of what we use it for,
for auditing is, is a little bit different.
It's about, it's usually more about market expansion.
Um, but product service development
is part of market expansion.
Uh, and again, AI is incredible, um,
at designing new products and services.
I like it is now pretty common for us to come up
with a concept, validate it,
and in a leadership team meeting, basically say,
this sits the market in, in seven days, um,
which is something that, you know, would've taken
usually six, six weeks plus, uh, in the company previously.
And that's just a, because you have people enabled by AI
and who know how to do this,
and you have processes in place
that show them how to do this.
So yeah, it is very exciting.
Um, and the, that's,
that's why I think, you know, books like the Lean Startup,
I think someone said they're, they're reading it right now.
Uh, books like the Lean Startup are,
are actually becoming even more valuable today.
Uh, you know, even though, you know,
that concept which came out from five Steps in an epiphany,
it was like 20 years old.
Um, I actually think it's even more valuable today.
Okay. So we, uh, will go over some of the
homework for today.
Um, so this is the structure that we'll be using, uh,
for each of those Empower sessions.
Uh, so we're introducing it today
and starting with the sale to delivery side.
Um, what it is, is a pretty comprehensive assessment, uh,
to help you evaluate your core process, in this case,
the sale to delivery process.
Um, and the output of this prompt, which is a back
and forth conversation with AI is, uh, a score, right?
In terms of how effective, uh, you're using the process, uh,
as well as what I find is very important is your
owner involvement score.
Like, how much does the process
re depend on you, right?
So this is the heroic effort side,
and the idea is to over time,
IM improve both of those scores.
The cool thing about doing this, you know,
I originally had this as, um, like a, a program, right?
Uh, so is just software that that ran in our companies.
Um, but you always have to kind of tailor it
to, uh, your business.
The cool thing about doing this now with Claude
and with the Master prompt is Claude knows everything
that knows a a lot about your business.
Claude can give you examples
and tell you what good looks like in your business,
right, in each of these areas.
Um, and, uh, it also makes it way, way faster.
So one of the things you've probably already encountered,
but you'll see over and over and over again, um, is this,
if you have the master prompt as context,
whenever you chat with ai, um, you know, you always ask it
to ask you questions, almost like interview,
ask you a question one at a time,
and answer its own question based on
what it knows about you, giving you the chance to edit
or confirm before moving on to the next question.
Uh, I use that so often that I actually just have it like
in my, uh, copy
and paste constantly, um, just in case for whatever reason,
my, uh, master prompter gets to do it.
It saves so much time, uh,
but it also generates tons of insights, right?
So, because you'll, you'll be doing it and going through
and answering a question, uh, or it'll ask you a question
and it'll come up with these ideas
that you didn't even really think about.
And then you can go back and forth
and like develop that out quickly.
Um, the other thing that this does, each
of these assessments also generates an output that's, uh,
loads into your master prompt.
And so your master prompt
and Claude, every time you talk to it in the future,
understands where, uh, some of your, uh, opportunities lie,
uh, and also where some of your strengths are,
uh, in each of your businesses.
And, uh, so by the end of this,
your master prompt like understands each of your processes,
uh, how involved you are, uh, and where you need to approve.
And I'll quickly add Hayden, I know
for myself when I started doing this internally with you,
what, what's cool, and perhaps some
of the beta people can relate to this is in that process
of having a conversation, um, you also, especially early on,
you start to see
where the AI doesn't get right on your company.
And so instead of just, you know, typing a prompt
and then it putting, creating an output, uh, a big delta
for me was going through the assessment,
but then also seeing this is great.
It's saving me a bunch of time that would've taken
so much longer if I were to ever do this.
But also in this output of the question that I'm,
it's clearly not right here,
or if in 20% of it where you get to correct it
for when you actually store it in the master prompt as a,
as a final artifact to Hayden's point.
So I, I think you'll all find that to be very,
very consistent as you build this from scratch.
So we've gone over already in a previous session, the sort
of the three layers, um,
of business process from a higher level.
Um, and so we're focusing today on sale to delivery,
which is part of the customer lifecycle layer,
which is the revenue generating sort
of customer facing layer.
Um, each
of those other sessions we talked about are mainly focused
in the, in the customer lifecycle.
There are two enabling processes, uh, there,
which is the financial performance management
and the hire to retire that we're covering, again, two areas
that I find, um, businesses
really benefit from seeing what good looks like,
and also two areas that I find
that AI can, can help improve.
We don't spend a ton
of time in the strategic planning, uh, layer.
Uh, in fact, I would say like the product service
design is one of 'em.
And we've done in, in the marketing session,
we do go over sort of the ICP and brand identity a bit.
Uh, and I guess in the onboarding, sort
of the session zero stuff, we covered some
of this in the businesses entity.
Um, but that's something that you
can continue to build upon.
Um, and frankly, I don't find,
I don't think strategy is the reason most small,
small businesses, um, struggle.
So,
so quick visual reminder, right?
We've got market to lead, lead to sale.
So lead to sale is you have a lead,
you sell them on your product, sale to delivery is from
that first sale to
a moment in delivery of your definition.
Um, and, and I mentioned this
because depending on your business,
there's no right way to do this.
There's only the right way
that you define it within your own business.
Um, but depending on your business, you may decide,
maybe you have, like me, I have businesses that have, uh,
you know, delivery cycles
that are sometimes two years long, right?
So where do I wanna define sort of delivery starting
in a construction company
or in, you know, a project based company, it's quite common
to say, sale to delivery involves the, uh, onboarding,
the setting of expectations, the internal planning, um,
and perhaps some of like the, the vendor management
involved, whereas delivery
to success is the longer actual sort of construction
or project base at work.
So again, not really a, a wrong way
to do this in terms of that separation.
Just important that you define what it's
the, the scoring, uh, is your standard sort
of Vogue Magazine type of quiz.
Uh, so seven, seven points, uh, down to zero points.
Uh, they, they all kind of combine that
to this a hundred point system.
Um, in terms of your process maturity or, or the clarity
and effectiveness, the owner involvement
is zero points to five points.
Uh, and so five points, the, you know,
more points, the better.
I five points in owner involvement basically means you're
not at all involved or you're only informed, uh,
when something's done doesn't require your input whatsoever.
Uh, it totally normal. By the way, I do not expect,
and most of my business don't have seven points across the
board for, uh, every single one of these, right?
And so this, this is a lot of the sevens are aspirational.
Um, a lot of the sevens are unrealistic if you have a
smaller, like a, a much smaller business, uh, and,
and they simply define what, you know,
excellent systems might look like in a more mature business.
So that's totally fine. Um,
and it's totally fine if you have a five
and you never want to get to a seven, um,
because you never really want to be a,
a massive scaled company.
Um, but I think it's still important to, in most cases,
you'll likely find something where you're a one or a three.
Uh, and those are areas of, uh, you know, probably immediate
ai, uh, inclusion.
Yeah, I would say definitely Hayden on, we, we determined,
um, a hundred percent of people are stage one
to stage three in the call.
So this is exactly,
I mean, the, the points here
or three points, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So the effectiveness, uh, allows you
to identify deficiencies.
Uh, the owner involvement allows you
to identify areas for delegation.
Um, and obviously the, the assessment overall
and the things that spits out gives
you targeted suggestions.
Um, I actually recently was, I, I've been
creating a curriculum for teams, uh, on the side and,
and, and delivering it.
And I've been applying it to myself as, as I go, uh,
and kind of we did a similar assessment
and it, like, the thing that it did
for me about two weeks ago, I would say, saved me 500 hours.
And I was telling Josh the other day that
if someone had told me that I could do this,
I would've paid a hundred grand for
it at that moment in time.
Um, so ai, AI can be kind of lifesaving.
Um, in this case for me, it ident it,
defendant identified a deficiency, suggested I delegate it,
and then as I began delegating it
and creating the processes for this one thing
that I was doing, I realized,
why don't I just spin up cloud code
and have Claude go through my processes, um, which I did.
And it took a 15 to 25 hour output
and turned it into about a, about a 45 minute output.
Um, and that's something that I'm gonna have to do probably
a couple hundred times in the next three months.
So pretty, pretty cool.
Okay. What I'll do now, Hayden, um,
is I'll just kinda walk through all of
that at a high level just
because I've been doing this alongside with everyone, um,
just to make sure they see what this is looking like.
Um, okay, so inside everything that he just went over
with you, I'll, I'll, I'll walk you all through
so you can see my screen.
And so, as he mentioned, we're doing sale to delivery.
So let me, let me start with the prompts. Okay.
So this is what immediately
after the session, you're going to have access
to after session three.
Okay? This is the sale to delivery prompt
to assess your organization's performance in sale delivery
process, which he just explained.
So what you're going to do simply is just copy this.
Um, this is rather long.
I wanna say it's, so, it's about 17 pages.
I'm not gonna copy the whole thing right now,
but literally, all you have to do, have to do is copy it,
come back to Claude, come into here, paste it,
and start a new chat to run that assessment.
Now again, um, you'll be able to rename it.
That will be your, your third chat inside the project.
As of right now, just sale to delivery assessment.
And that will give you, if I click on here,
that will give you an artifact down here that you would,
again, your choice.
The, the most seamless way to add this
to the project is come here
and just hit add to project, literally one click.
If you are like me, you will be gathering a lot
of knowledge documentation.
So I prefer to name this specifically.
So you would just download this, come back to your project,
hit plus, um, upload file from device, um,
and then you would name it that way.
So you start with sale to delivery.
The next thing is the four level documentation that,
that Hayden talked about here.
So again, it's just a copy paste.
This is just a text document.
So again, you're going to copy this entire thing.
It's a lot. I won't do that right now.
And then you'll just come over here to the plus
hit plus hit add text context
or content, excuse me, name it, and paste it right here.
And that will paste the four level documentation
as a text file right here in your project.
Okay? So then the final thing is going to level one
and two SOPs.
Okay? So you see right here,
all the instructions I'm going over are up here for you
to follow step by step.
But after that, all you simply do is copy this, go to Claude
and pop it in here as a new chat and just start.
Um, I, I named it sale to delivery, SOP,
which I believe it says for you to do up here,
correct name it, sale to delivery, SOP.
And once you complete this,
you will then paste this prompt in.
And one thing to be aware of,
especially if you're a very small organization, is
that a lot of time AI will build a very vast plan, um,
in terms of, you know, blueprints for you to follow.
So prompt three is gonna be the last thing that you,
you put into this last chat,
completing the, the previous two.
And it's just gonna say, do these.
So p SOPs seem over-engineered for a company the size
of mine, whether you're one to 10 people,
and a lot of times you will find
that is absolutely the case.
And so yes, if the answer is yes,
it will then refine those things.
Okay, so going back to Claude, you will then see
all of these are in here.
You, you can have more files than this.
Again, I'm just sort of doing this internally
with you just so you can have a visual.
Um, so I only have four.
You could have a lot more than that,
but ultimately I downloaded those
and put all of those blueprints into my project files.
So from the first one we had our master prompt.
Um, the second one we had, uh, a total of five,
and you're running the sale to reassessment the four level,
uh, documentation framework,
and then all of the blueprints that come from your process.
Okay. So you can come back to the session
with any and all things.
And that is exactly how you are going
to complete this assignment following this session.
So, um, I will, I think we can open it up, Hayden,
if anybody has any questions.
And then I'll just kind of recap that as we sort
of end the call today.
Let me, uh, just quickly before,
or ask people put their questions in, I just want to
list some of the reasons why.
Uh, so why, what are we doing when we actually put
that giant four levels in?
We're putting that into our project, so in our master prompt
so that in the future, uh,
we are sharing the same language with ai.
Um, process is one of those things just like KPIs
and some other terms that doesn't actually have like a
uniform definition on how it's handled.
And so one of the benefits, uh,
of the Empower program is actually a process taxonomy
that we can share with our, with our teams,
but also share with ai.
So that copying and pasting that in gives it that taxonomy
and it references that taxonomy every time you talk to it.
Um, and then on the, you know, some
of the prompts are simplistic
or they seem, they seem very short.
So it says something like, give me two level two blueprints,
or, you know, generate a level one process.
Um, it can only do that
because once you've already put in
that giant four level thing,
it's referencing everything you mentioned on
what is a blueprint, what is a core process, et cetera.
Hopefully that was helpful.
So Hayden, um, Montgomery asks,
when you wanna revisit a document sale to delivery, uh,
SOP in, in this case, do you go back to that original chat
where you initially started and have the convo there?
Or do you have a, a new chat
and then delete the one with the new one?
What is best practice?
Going back to the chat, um, is best if you want
to con continue the conversation.
Um, if you wanna just revisit a document
and access it, there's, um, you,
you probably don't need to use Claude for that.
Uh, there's, there's other tools, uh,
we'll be introducing stage three, which is a way to kind
of look at all your documentation and update it from within.
Um, but yeah, within cloud I'd definitely say, you know,
have a single, uh, conversation.
Try not to split up too many into
too many different conversations.
Have a, have a naming convention.
Um, and when if you happen to do two to three conversations,
like rename them as old or archived.
Um, so, you know, 'cause
otherwise you'll be, I've definitely spent a lot
of time just trying to find the right
conversation. Yeah, thank you.
If it's helpful too, when, when I've revisited stuff in
that form, actually just put the date, it's a name
to the same, I just put the date on it.
Um, and sometimes, uh, again, it's, it's very helpful
for the context to pick the conversation up,
but if you also somehow hit your sort of a
limit in, in a chat just by chance,
you can always take the artifact
and then take the artifact if you're, I assume that's
what you might be revising anyway,
and just start a new chat, say, start
with this finalized artifact
and then you can sort of prompt it on
where you wanna go from it as well as if that's helpful.
You can also star chats, um, which is, is useful
until you've starred 200 chats and no longer is useful.
Nice, nice precursor there for what he blog looks like.
Um, what other questions do you guys have?
Okay, Jonas? Yeah, you got your hand up? Go ahead.
Yep. Perfect. Thanks. Uh, quick question, uh, to you guys.
Um, so Christina and I, she's also on the call.
We're basically a team
and we were wondering how we can use Claude best as a team.
So she's doing it, I'm doing it simultaneously.
We have a team plan, we share the information,
but how can we get the most out of it,
basically working simultaneously, should, you know?
Yeah, that's basically the question. Short,
Uh, what are each of your roles in the
company and how large is the company?
Uh, very small. Uh, less than 10 employees.
Uh, Christina's the owner. I'm basically the appointed CEO.
Okay. Um, yeah, so I I, what a lot
of people have done in the past is they've gone
through the exercises and then created a new chat
and basically saying, here's my version,
here's Christina's version.
What compare both of them, right?
What are some of the, uh, divergences between the two?
Uh, and also what are some of the commonalities?
And, uh, it's that it can be very, uh,
very insightful, uh,
because naturally there'll be things that you're closer to
that you know, you maybe understand better than Christina
or there, and there'll be things that she's closer to
and it, it's, it gives you that single point of truth
or single source of truth.
Um, so I find that that's very, very helpful.
Um, the other thing that you can do,
and this is what we're doing in the teams program, is
you can use the personal preferences in Claude, uh,
which is, I basically go to settings at the,
in the bottom left corner
and go to from there you have personal preferences
and you can paste in information about you mm-hmm.
And your role in the company.
And Christie, Nick can also do that, do that about her
and her role in the company,
and that'll, that will be added to the project.
And so for that reason, over time, you will actually have
slightly divergent master prompts
that are actually more about and more useful to you.
So that's what we teach teams to do is that they understand
what process AI understands exactly
what processes Josh is involved in, right.
Versus Hayden, um, and how he touches certain things
and his aspirations in the company, um,
which can become quite useful.
Cool. I guess we're on
A good, just quickly add on to that
because we had that discussion.
So just concern concerning the master prompts,
do we both upload our, in our respective master prompts?
Will that not confuse Claude?
So you would both have your own separate project?
Um, okay. Yeah.
So you'd have, Christina had the company master prompt
according to Christina and the company master
fund according to Jonas.
Um, and then again, in,
in those sessions you can actually take some of the,
the outputs, um, and you can see compare these two
and tell gimme some insights.
Great, thank you. And,
and practically Christina, just for clarity,
so essentially you would say, Hey, this, I just ran this,
uh, sale to delivery assessment,
and then when you are done with it, you go in the same chat
and say that Jonas actually ran this,
and you can paste in his end assessment
and say, try to find the discrepancies
because we're talking about the same company.
And then in the same chat it'll show that.
And I know internally, um, we've done this
and it's interesting
because as, as an operator, there, there,
there will be a lot of things
that maybe you don't see more on day to day.
And to Hayden's point, vice versa. Right?
The only, the only other way I've seen this
for people in the cohort do it, um, just
because it wasn't mentioned is the o the,
the CEO like built it.
Um, and then you could have like, hey, a sale,
I have a sales person that like they end up owning a thing,
but al almost after you built the, the foundation
of the master prompt, then you have your director layer
or whatever, actually do what they own
to then revisit the exact same process.
Okay, thanks a lot. Yep.
The only only reason you may want to, uh,
at some point use the same project would be if you fall
behind, um,
and it doesn't make sense for you
to both double up on the same work.
Um, that, that would be the only time that I'd say, okay,
maybe start sharing your project with Jonas or vice versa
and you guys can kind of divide and conquer.
Um, but as long as that's not the case,
then I would say you'll get a lot out
of having your own projects. Appreciate
It. Makes a lot of sense.
Yeah.
Okay, Montgomery, hands up.
My question is revolving around how best
to implement this in a team environment when you want some
information to be restricted and some to be open.
So in your case, Hayden,
when you have many different companies
and different operators within those companies,
how have you looked at the hierarchical structure for
what someone in a department can see
and cannot yet still keeping the whole methodology fluid?
So at the end of this, uh, at the end of the cohort,
so ideally right now, you should not be sharing, you know,
your developing master prompt with your team.
Um, but at the end of this, you'll,
you'll actually create different versions
of the master fraud for different team members.
So for example, your leadership team may have, you know,
a fully shown version, right?
Whereas, and your finance might have finance team might have
access to more finance, uh,
but maybe you want your sales team to only have
to not have access to finance or not have access to hr.
Um, it's actually very easy to do within your project.
By the time you have your fully done master prompt,
you literally just tell Claude,
look at all your project sources
and create a new output, uh, a new artifact
with a new output of my master prompt minus any sensitive
data, right?
Or minus any financial data
or minus any, and go back and forth.
And usually you should say show, you know, do not redo,
do not take anything else out.
Show me exactly what you took out, et cetera. Right?
Uh, but then you, you can create a new project with that
and then you can share that project with
your sales team as an example.
Um, and it's not only confidentiality reasons,
it's also just context reasons.
Uh, it may not make sense.
And, and at the end of this,
or even partially through this, uh, your,
your master prompt will grow
and it will make sense to start moving some
of your process out of your master prompt.
Uh, and this is one of the ways
that you can do that as well, right?
So you could have, um, uh, as an example, I have a master,
a separate master prompt that has, uh, context of all
of the curriculum, um, for a program.
I wouldn't use that in my day-to-day master prompt
because it would be a total waste
of tokens and, and context.
Got it. Thank you. Yep.
And also, if this is practical in any way, I, I connected
with a gentleman yesterday, I had a call with
and he, uh, he was from the beta
and what he, he is a very small team.
Um, and all he did was he, he created, you know,
just like we do in the project, he created his master prompt
to completion and then he took all those documents
and just put it in his personal preferences, similar
to Hayden talked about.
And then in the, in the project,
he just removed things like finance is the, the popular one.
So we'll just, I don't know exactly what he removed,
but then essentially everything else was in the project
and he, he then shared the project with his team,
excluding the stuff in the project that would be sensitive,
he didn't want his team to see.
So, And speaking of that as a quick follow up,
maybe we'll get into it in a subsequent uh, meeting,
but with connecting to Google drives, I was playing around
with what I can enable.
I guess if it's a team project
and everybody has access, you can't connect it
to your drive, but if you start the project
in your own, connect it to your drive and then make it team
or public, then you can,
and I kind of tripped up on
what was the best methodology there for when you want
to use your Google Drive to reference documents.
Yeah. So you have a, you have a,
a company G suite account I would assume?
Yeah. Yes. So you, you're connecting that G Suite account
to Claude,
and then you would want to have your folder within
that company drive, not within a personal drive.
Okay. That just silly question
then that's cleared up. Thank you.
Yeah, yeah, no problem.
Actually, uh, in previous versions of the cohort, I,
I didn't recommend using Google Drive, uh,
because it wasn't working properly.
Now it is, um,
and it actually does take up to date, actually,
interestingly, notebook LM does not keep up
to date Google Drive, but Claude does.
So if you put your master prompt in Google,
in a Google Doc in Claude,
and then you edit that Google doc,
then Claude will will take the most recent version of
that Google Doc for whatever
reason, notebook LM does not do that.
When you add it to Notebook lm, it takes
that state in history and it does not take any revisions.
Hmm. So within clo,
within Claude you can actually create tools
or paired with Claude, you can actually create tools to, uh,
dynamically update Google Docs, right through
through scripts, uh, in order
to keep different versions of master.
We'll get into this at the end,
but in order to keep different versions of master prompts up
to date, uh, you can't do that with Google,
even though it's a Google product.
Thank you. Uh, let's see.
Lee, I gave Claude my master prompt and our org chart
and had it make a version per role type across the org.
That way each person has our master prompt
with appropriate levels of information.
Awesome. Yeah, just like anything guys, there's no,
in business and in life, there's no one way to,
to do anything.
So this is cool to see and discuss.
And then Nancy, can that work
with personal Google Drive versus G Suite, um, for business?
Um, do you know that Hayden, I assume it would.
I I mean I think you can connect
your personal Google Drive.
I don't see why not. I have never done it. Um,
That's the error I had when I tried it first to do it
with my personal and then share it
as a public and it wouldn't work. Uh,
Okay, interesting. Did
That from linking Claude, your Claude team to Google
as a, but you could do it what individually to yours?
I don't just, can you I got lost in there
As best as I can remember.
As I was playing around with it, I connected at first my,
uh, Google drive,
my personal Google Drive to a team account.
And that created problems.
And as Hayden said, it needs to be done to the G suite.
But if you connected in your, uh, private project,
in your team account,
but in your own world of private, then it's okay.
That's my understanding.
And I suspect if you don't have a Claude Teams account
and you just have like a Claude personal account,
you would be fine just connecting it
to your personal Google Drive.
Another question while I, so the, the stage three,
which I got a little bit of a view of, is, is
that's something that actually would substitute putting your
stuff onto Google Drive and organizing in a certain way?
Like should we wait? Yes.
Yes. So I'm actually introducing
that in the homework today.
Um, so it's,
I mean the introduction here is really just you register,
you're gonna put your first process in.
Uh, it's a lot easier to do it step by step as opposed
to do it all at once at the end.
Um, and,
and yes, it's the, the purpose of stage three is
as people graduate the cohort, as our own teams did this,
you encounter the same predictable problems, which is like,
how do I share my master prompts
and versions of my master prompt with different people?
How do I actually access and share in version control
and update my processes properly?
Um, and then stage three also does it with an AI agent
that can do everything in batch, which is kind of cool.
Um, so yeah, we're, we're including that.
You're welcome to use it. Uh,
we're also suggesting if you wanna use a Google
Drive technique, you can do that too.
Um, but yeah, hopefully that helps you. I use
Both. Do you use both?
No, I just use stage three and cloud code. Yeah. Yeah.
For clarity by the way, you're gonna, you're gonna kind
of have three options at towards the end where, where,
you know, a precursor,
but essentially you, you, you could build it
and decide to use cloud teams
and sort of share that with your team.
That's kind of one choice.
Uh, there's, you know, some clunky, uh, sharing and,
and different things that some challenges there.
Then you could use Google Drive
or if you use Microsoft,
whatever your company internally
stores document knowledge currently.
Um, and what, what we've seen, especially
after taking calls with a lot
of these businesses post cohort is as much as
that is super helpful in terms
of documenting your process on, we'll take Google Drive,
Nancy, um, what we find is that as much as it's documented,
the team members of that organization are not going
through Google Drive and going through all of
that documentation and pretty much 99.9%
of the time never will happen.
And so that's kind of the challenge with that.
And to Hayden's point,
that's why it's called stage three software.
He sort of invented it during the,
as we were delivering these cohorts to solve
that exact problem.
So well excited to give everybody access to that, to, uh,
store share with user gates, like share only these things
to these different team members while also seeing like your
blueprints, workflows and, and RACI charts as well.
Alright, any other questions?
One more that I saw that Leo, it was, it was racing,
so I was going very fast at the end,
but to try to put the, into the, the processes like copy
that it, the Google Drive was not allowing us me to copy.
I got a message that said, uh, copy and paste is disabled.
Yeah, it's happened a couple of times.
The only reason that's happened is
because of the owner of the document.
Actually, Lee pointed this out in circle
and so the, the last, it was, I think it was like a set, um,
doc 2.4.
It just had, we, so we, we duplicated
that is no longer a problem inside the curriculum.
Uh, shout out Lee for, for pointing it out.
'cause I think you were doing it right
after the, uh, the session, so I appreciate
It. Right? No, because I did it like
one minute
before getting on the call. It still happened to me.
Yeah. So apologies for that.
It was just taking it from the previous, um, document
and the, the owner, um, you know, created those settings.
So we just had to dupe it and create new docs.
Okay, cool.
Awesome. Great.
Well good to see everyone
and uh, nice to meet a bunch of you for the first time.
Yeah, we will. Uh, yeah, have a good weekend.
You got your, your first assessment to run.
So Monday will be pretty cool to kind of see
where everybody's at through that.
You know, it should take you, you guys about an hour to,
to kind of comb through
everything that, that we went through.
And then we will meet again Monday at the same time
to talk about next steps.
Great. Thank you. Thanks everyone.
Have a good rest of your day. Thanks everyone. Talk soon.